## **Matt Wilson**

Front End Developer

### About me

I have over 5 years experience in the web development industry and for most of that time have focused on front-end architecture. I'm comfortable in both large and small agile development teams and enjoy new challenges. I'm enthusiastic about my work and pride myself on attention to detail.

### **Skills & Competencies**

JavaScript (ES2015) HTML5, CSS3

SASS

React

Node

CSS methodologies (BEM, SMACSS, ITCSS)

Babel, Gulp, Webpack

Handlebars.js

**Bootstrap** 

Jasmine, Mocha, Chai, Enzyme

Docker, Vagrant

**jQuery** 

PHP

Google suite (Tag Manager, Publisher Tag, Analytics)

Accessibility (WAI-ARIA)

Git

Agile Scrum

# **Experience**

Mar 2017 - Sep 2017

Front-end Developer at the Royal Opera House

-----

Primary developer responsible for re-engineering every aspect of the front end. Restructured and migrated all SASS. Tasked with configuring and maintaining the front-end build tools. Provided analysis and recommendations about JavaScript frameworks. Worked closely with design to implement an updated style guide. Migrated functionality over to React.

Sep 2014 - Dec 2016

UI Developer at Immediate Media Co.

----

Part of an agile scrum team responsible for the Radio Times website. Tasked with making the site fully responsive and accessible across all devices. Primary developer responsible for the modernisation of the TV listings web app. Helped to introduce front end coding standards and the use of linting tools. Setup build tools using Gulp & Webpack. Worked extensively on integrating third-party APIs. Researched and implemented unit tests using Jasmine. Regularly participated in company hackathons designed to encourage innovation.

Jun 2012 - Apr 2014

Web Developer at Digital Trip Ltd.

----

Responsible for delivering both white-label & bespoke websites to a large number of clients in the travel industry. Created a number of new modules for the company's in-house CMS. Assisted in the development of the company's CSS style guide, for use across their entire product range. Integrated multi-lingual and multi-currency functionality. Direct technical support for clients.

Aug 2010 - Aug 2011

Junior Software Developer/Intern at PokerStars.

----

Assisted in the maintenance of the company's web based reporting suite. Implemented improved navigation options across the system. Prototyped an account tracking system for the Treasury Department. Worked closely with the IT Security Department to manage access privileges across the system.

### Education

2012

BSc(Hons) Computing from Bournemouth University

Awarded 2:1

----

2005

A-Levels from Castle Rushen High School Computing, Art Graphics & Product Design